I always love coming to New York and interviewing my favorite pop stars. I did Gaga Down the Road here somewhere at Johnson.
ニューヨークに来るたび、好きなポップスターにインタビューできるの、いつも大好きなんだよね。このへんのどこか、ジョンソンでガガのダウン・ザ・ロードをやったんだ。
Oh, yeah. No, I saw that one. Um, we're going to look at a video. What's it for?
ああ、うん。いや、あれは見たよ。えっと、ビデオ見るんだよね。何用なの？
This is for party. For party. Couple of questions before you watch this video about the song. Third song on the record samples Madonna.
これはパーティー用。パーティーの。この曲について、ビデオ見る前にちょっと質問。レコードの3曲目がマドンナをサンプリングしてる。
Yep. Why did you choose that? And is there any relationship with Madonna existing previous forthcoming? Like what's the story behind using music?
うん。なんでそれを選んだの？ マドンナとの関係って、今あるのか、前からなのか、これからなのか？ 音楽を使う裏のストーリーは何？
Well, so first of all, Madonna like a prayer is like one of my first things that I remember in my whole life. She's always been important to me.
えっと、まずマドンナの『Like a Prayer』、ライク・ア・プレイヤーは、人生で覚えてる最初のもののひとつみたいなんだよ。彼女はずっと僕にとって大事だった。
But then um I was actually thinking about that Gaga interview where she's like bus club, another club, whatever, you know, listening. And I was like, yeah, that's kind of like a how a good weekend feels.
でもそのあと、あのガガのインタビューのこと実際考えてて、彼女がバス・クラブ、また別のクラブ、まあなんでも、聴いてるみたいな。僕は、うん、いい週末ってそういう感じだよなって。
Like I think when I'm my happiest, when I'm partying is when I cuz I'll put these like kind of rules up in my head where I'm like, "Oh, well it's it's 3:00.
僕がいちばん幸せなとき、パーティーしてるときって、頭の中にこういうルール立てちゃうからなんだよね。「ああ、もう3時だ。
I should probably go home." You know what I mean? And the best thing ever is when I like push through and I'm like, "No, why am I setting these imposing these rules on myself?
たぶん帰ったほうがいい」って。わかる？ でいちばん最高なのは、押し切って「いや、なんで自分にこういうルール課して、押し付けてるんだ？」ってなるとき。
Like, let me just keep going kind of thing." Um, and I feel like that's when I have a lot of fun.
「このまま続けちゃおう」みたいな。で、そういうときがいちばん楽しいんだよ。
And so that was the starting point for the song. And the song is this like cyclical kind of like thing that just keeps going and going and going.
それが曲の出発点だった。曲はこういう循環みたいなもので、ただ続いて、続いて、続いていく。
And then there's a moment in the song where it cuts to these like breaths and just like the sub. And to me, it's like all of a sudden you're you're kind of like at the party.
で曲のなかに、こういう息にカッと切り替わって、ただサブだけ、って瞬間がある。僕には、急にパーティーにいるみたいな感じなんだ。
it's like super wide or whatever and then it immediately goes inward and you're just in yourself and it's like that moment where you know like the music is kind of like pulsing through
めっちゃワイドとかなんだけど、すぐ内側に入って、ただ自分の中にいて、音楽がなんか脈打って通っていく、あの瞬間みたいな
your entire body and you can kind of like feel the heat of one of the lights on your face and and music by Madonna is playing at this party and you're just kind
体じゅうに。ライトのひとつの熱が顔に感じられて、このパーティーでマドンナの音楽がかかってて、ただなんか
of like lost in in that moment and so um that was why I wanted to to That's cool. So what's up with the video?
その瞬間に迷子になってるみたいな。だからそれを、それをやりたかったんだ。かっこいいね。で、ビデオはどうなってるの？
The video you didn't have to reach out to Madonna to get the sample.
ビデオは、サンプルもらうのにマドンナに連絡しなくてよかったんだよね。
I I did. You did? Yes. She's fine. She was lovely about it.
し、したよ。したの？ うん。彼女は大丈夫だった。それについてすごく優しかった。
Awesome. Made it super easy. I I haven't met her yet. I'm going to meet her I think for the first time in like a week.
最高。めっちゃ簡単にしてくれた。まだ会ったことなくて。たぶん1週間くらいで初めて会うと思う。
Really? Um I hope we'll see if it ends up happening. But um the video, so basically Gordon Bonsteiner, who I work with on all my music videos, him and I were talking about this song Party, and
ほんと？ えっと、実際に起きるかどうか見てみよう。でもビデオは、基本的にゴードン・ボンシュタイナー、ミュージックビデオは全部一緒にやってる人なんだけど、彼と僕はこの曲パーティーの話をしてて、
we were talking about how I think for both of us, like partying is actually something that we take quite seriously and something that I think is like really important to like humanity
僕ら両方にとって、パーティーするって実はかなり本気で受け止めてることで、人類にとって本当に大事なことだと思う、って話してて
you know what I mean? Just like almost like an act of resistance fully. And and this idea of like letting loose, I think, is something that's very innate and like required.
わかる？ ほとんど完全に、抵抗の行為みたいな。で、ハメを外すっていうこの考えは、すごく生まれつきのもので、必要なことだと思う。
And so well then surely if it's innate surely people have always partied in some capacity and especially queer people you know like I think I remember the first time I set foot in
だから、生まれつきなら、人はきっと昔からなんらかの形でパーティーしてきたはずで、特にクィアの人たち。初めて足を踏み入れたときのこと、覚えてるんだ
a gay bar and it was like I was in Cape Town and the feeling of not being the minority for the first time in my whole life.
ゲイバーに。ケープタウンにいて、人生で初めて自分が少数派じゃないっていう感覚。
Like you keep all of this like it feels like a pressure cooker inside of you for the first like in my case 15 years of my life of not telling anyone.
全部これを中に抱え込んでて、圧力鍋みたいな感じなんだよ。僕の場合、誰にも言わないまま最初の15年間。
And you're a kid as well, so you're like terrified. It's like a real kind of tent pole moment, I think, in a queer person's life. And like through like resistance, night life becomes this like sacred space.
しかもまだ子供だから、怖くてしょうがない。クィアの人の人生で、本当にテントポールみたいな瞬間だと思う。抵抗を通して、ナイトライフがこの聖なる空間になる。
Can I see it? Yeah, of course. I'm excited.
見ていい？ うん、もちろん。楽しみだよ。
Conquest is nearly behind us. Oh you went in.
征服はほぼ僕らの背後だ。おお、入っていったね。
Fire blaze from one end of the realm to the other.
炎が領域の端から端まで燃え広がる。
This isn't cosplay. This is serious. For at long last a party in the park, party in the bush is epic.
これはコスプレじゃない。本気だ。ついに長く待ち望んで、パーティー・イン・ザ・パーク、パーティー・イン・ザ・ブッシュは壮大だ。
Party of the cold. Party in the day. Party in my house. Party on the way to the party at the park. [music] Sick. Sick. Nice. brilliant, man.
コールドのパーティー。昼のパーティー。家でのパーティー。パークのパーティーへ行く途中のパーティー。やば。やば。ナイス。最高だよ。
Thank you. Brilliant. What a crazy concept, right? In like the most authentic way as well.
ありがとう。最高。なんて狂ったコンセプトだよね？ しかもいちばん本物なやり方で。
Like it actually looks like a proper historical period drama.
実際、ちゃんとした歴史の時代劇に見えるんだよ。
The concept itself is like quite camp which I love obviously.
コンセプト自体はかなりキャンプで、もちろん僕はそれが好きなんだ。
But then I was like to Gordon, we have to make it like the most cinematically gorgeous thing in the entire world. You know what I mean?
でもゴードンに、世界でいちばん映画的にゴージャスなものにしなきゃ、って言ったんだ。わかる？
Like it has to look like No, it has to look like the favorite or something like that. You know what I mean?
いや、そう見えなきゃ、いや、『the favorite』みたいなものに見えなきゃ、みたいな。わかる？
Yeah. 2 hours outside of London and it was amazing.
うん。ロンドンの外、2時間で、最高だった。
Yeah. I was shook. Like when we arrived at the battle scene, I was like, "What the is going on?"
うん。ショックだったよ。バトルシーンに着いたとき、「なにが起きてんだ？」って。
Like this is the craziest thing I've ever seen in my life. Um, for the voiceover in the beginning, I really wanted like I think I love the idea of this like queer lineage as well, you know
人生で見たなかでいちばん狂ったものだった。えっと、最初のボイスオーバーは、このクィアの系譜みたいなアイデアが本当に好きで、
like through night life and through kind of these spaces, these like party spaces
ナイトライフを通して、こういう空間、パーティーの空間を通して、
there's this like education that kind of happens where I feel like the older generation or the generation above kind of like ushers in and and kind of educates the the newbies.
こういう教育が起きるんだよね。上の世代、ひとつ上の世代が、新入りを導き入れて、教えていくみたいな。
And so yeah, this idea that that get has been passed down and down and down like so Ian Mckllen was like I asked him if he would do a voiceover for the beginning
だから、そのgetが下へ下へと渡されてきたっていう考え。だからイアン・マッケレンに、冒頭の
of of this video. You wrote him a letter.
このビデオのボイスオーバーをやってくれないか頼んだ。手紙を書いたんだよね。
Um I made him a video. Okay. And then he sent me a video back, right?
えっと、彼にビデオを作ったんだ。わかった。そしたら彼がビデオを送り返してきた、だよね？
He was in full Gandalf gear and he Gandalf he is Gandalf in the video that he sent me in his like trailer.
完全なGandalfの格好で、彼はGandalf、彼はGandalfなんだ、僕に送ってきたビデオのなかで、自分のトレーラーみたいなところで。
Um and then he used like the Lord of the Rings sound team to record this voiceover for me.
えっと、それから『ロード・オブ・ザ・リング』の音響チームを使って、このボイスオーバーを僕のために録ってくれた。
So like all of my correspondence was with like the production company who makes those movies and I'm like emailing them like to get the files and stuff and it was awesome.
だからやり取りは全部、あの映画を作ってる制作会社とで、ファイルをもらうためにメールしたりして、最高だった。
That's incredible. Yeah, he's legend. Oh my god. You just want him to do a voiceover and he he took you to Middle Earth. Yeah, literally.
信じられない。うん、彼は伝説だよ。なんてこと。ボイスオーバーやってほしいだけなのに、中つ国まで連れていかれた。うん、文字どおり。
But yeah, it was really fun. But the choreography is beautiful as well. Amazing. And I and I've loved to see that over the course of these last two albums.
でもうん、本当に楽しかった。振付も美しいよね。すごい。この最後の2枚のアルバムを通して、それを見られて好きなんだ。
You know, you really embracing movement in a in a really free way. It's like you're sort of going through each stage of your version of the perfect pop trajectory.
動きを、本当に自由な形で受け入れてるよね。君なりの完璧なポップの軌跡の、各ステージを進んでるみたいだ。
Do you know what I mean? Well, that's an interesting thing about this album is like the sort of poppy like dancy side of this album comes with so much like self-awareness.
わかる？ このアルバムの面白いところは、ポップでダンシーな側に、ものすごい自意識がついてくることなんだよ。
I would say it's almost like a little bit meta or something like that where it's like like for example there's a song called I do this for you on the album and I'm
ほとんどちょっとメタみたいだと思う。たとえばアルバムに「I do this for you」って曲があって、僕は
talking to you know this album is kind of dedicated to this like man that I don't know to this person that I have never met or maybe I have and I just don't
話してるんだけど、このアルバムは知らない男、会ったことない人、あるいは会ったのにまだ
haven't realized it yet but um you know it's like I was on tour with Charlie and we're having this like insane time that it just felt like an absolute like tsunami in in
気づいてない人に、なんか捧げられてるんだ。Charli xcxとツアーしてて、絶対的な津波みたいな、とんでもない時間を過ごしてて、
I think both of our lives at that time. And the whole thing I think was that it was a party for every single person who came to those shows.
あのとき僕ら両方の人生で、だと思う。全体として、あのショーに来た一人ひとりのためのパーティーだったと思う。
You know what I mean? It was like a nightclub. And so there was this like crazy crazy experience of like the ultimate connection and like joy and just feeling so like one with the world.
わかる？ ナイトクラブみたいだった。究極のつながりと喜びと、世界とひとつになってる感じの、狂った狂った体験があった。
And then I had no idea how to rationalize like the feeling that I would have when I would go home afterwards.
なのに、そのあと家に帰ったときの気持ちを、どうやって自分に説明したらいいか全然わからなかった。
And it wasn't just like there maybe an element of it is the crash from the show and everything like that, but
ショーのあとのクラッシュみたいな要素もあるかもしれないけど、それだけじゃなくて、
I think there was like yeah like the less kind of like pretty part of it was definitely like a deep loneliness, maybe even exacerbated by what was going on, you know?
きれいじゃない部分は、確実に深い孤独で、起きてることによって余計ひどくなってたかもしれない。わかる？
And so now in on this album in these like pop songs that I imagine that are happening on stage, there's this like element of something's not right.
だから今、このアルバムの、ステージで起きてるイメージのポップソングには、「何かがおかしい」って要素がある。
You know what I mean? Like something is kind of twisted about them a little bit. Like again, do this for you.
わかる？ ちょっとねじれてるんだよね。また、do this for you。
It starts off in this like bombastic song that I'm like, "Oh, I can't wait to do this live." And it's like in my head, these songs take place on stage.
ド派手な曲で始まって、「これライブでやるの待ちきれない」ってなる。頭の中では、これらの曲はステージで起きてる。
Like they're like it's like a story where you know I'm like fully on stage and then it breaks down into the bridge and like the lyric is like find hot singles in the
完全にステージにいる物語みたいで、それからブリッジで崩れて、歌詞がホットなシングルを見つけろ、みたいな、
Los Angeles area and it's like you know these pop-up ads that I'm getting when I go home. to tailored for you by the way which is even more like algorithmically attacking me and um [laughter] you are lonely.
ロサンゼルスエリアで。家に帰ると出てくるこういうポップアップ広告なんだ。ちなみに僕向けに仕立てられてて、アルゴリズムがもっと僕を攻めてきて、君は孤独だ。
I'm like, I know. But um but you know, so I think that like these things start to kind of like break. And it's not that it's not that either side of the album is more true than the other.
僕は、わかってるよ、って。でも、こういうものが壊れ始めていくんだと思う。アルバムのどちらの側も、もう片方より真実ってわけじゃない。
And that's something that I had to kind of like understand about this album was that my life was very there was like so much tension in it because I was experiencing these like
このアルバムについて理解しなきゃいけなかったのは、人生にものすごい緊張があったこと。こういう
extremes, you know, you know, even the coro and stuff like that. There's there's kind of like at least to me there's this like nod to this is this side of me that is very very very true.
両極端を経験してたから。わかる、わかる？ コロとかも。少なくとも僕には、自分のこの側がものすごく本当だっていう頷きがある。
I just wish it was like me 100% of the time. You know what I mean? And I wish it was me more than it actually is. You know what I mean?
それが100%の時間、自分だったらいいのに。わかる？ 実際より、もっと自分であってほしい。わかる？
Like it's like it started to at a certain point there was just this like disconnect that I needed to um like address somehow. You know, you can hear it on the record.
ある時点で、この断絶が始まって、なんとか向き合わなきゃいけなかった。レコードで聞こえるよ。
I mean you talked about it being two sides. It really is. It starts almost like an extension of of your previous record, you know
両面だって話してたよね。本当にそうなんだ。前のレコードの延長みたいに始まって、
an extension of that of that party with Charlie and and you know the the sort of euphoric trail that comes after that experience and then it slowly but surely does sink deeper and
Charli xcxとのあのパーティーの延長、あの体験のあとに来る陶酔の跡みたいなので、それからゆっくり確実に、もっと深く
deeper into this kind of mania. Yeah. This moment of self-reflection to the point of obsession of like what the you know, by the end of it.
深く、この種のマニアの中へ。うん。自分を見つめすぎて執着になる瞬間、「なにを、ってわかるよ」なところまで、終わりには。
I actually found it quite hopeful at the end and I think the last lyric is quite hopeful but it definitely it's it's a really honest record dressed up in great clothes.
俺は終わりはかなり希望があると思ったし、最後の歌詞はかなり希望があると思う。でも確実に、素敵な服を着た、本当に正直なレコードだ。
Thank you. I mean that's the thing is that like ultimately when I'm making something I know that I can only ever stand behind it if it's like true.
ありがとう。結局、何かを作ってるとき、本当のことじゃないと後ろに立てないってわかってるんだ。
And so even like this record is tougher for me because it's like it's like uglier. You know what I mean?
だからこのレコードは僕にとってよりきつい。もっと醜いから。わかる？
Like I think that the last time how fun to parade yourself around the world and be like, "Yeah I'm like feeling super connected to everyone and I'm like very open and I'm meeting all these people."
前回は、世界中で自分をパレードさせて、「うん、みんなと超つながってる感じで、すごくオープンで、いろんな人に会ってる」っていうのが、どれだけ楽しかったか。
It was honestly co I think co for me in Melbourne in between the lockdowns became this like mecca where it's the first time in many years that I wasn't traveling for work.
正直コ、僕にとってコは、メルボルンでロックダウンの合間に、何年かぶりに仕事で移動してないメッカみたいになったんだと思う。
Yeah. And I had the opportunity to like really connect with people in like a personal way. And so that was what I took into into that album.
うん。個人的な形で人と本当につながれる機会があった。それをあのアルバムに持っていったんだ。
And then this time around it's like yeah like I'm there like lyrics about jerking off and you know what I mean?
で今回は、うん、抜くことについての歌詞とかがある。わかる？
Like it's like okay it's like not the most fun thing to acknowledge. Well even that lyric hard and impatient. What a what a bar. It's like and I think Sexar is a great song.
OKみたいな、認めるのにいちばん楽しいことじゃない。あの「hard and impatient」、硬くて待ちきれない、なんて、なんてバーだ。で、Sexarはすごい曲だと思う。
I think you and Phineas and the team and your brother made a great piece of music there.
君とフィニアスとチームと、君の弟が、あそこで、すごい曲を作ったと思う。
Um, it's almost the closest thing to a ballad on the record, but that lyric really reminds you that this is there's a frustration going on here to all the success.
レコードのなかでバラードにいちばん近いものだけど、あの歌詞は、この成功の全部に対して苛立ちが起きてるってことを思い出させる。
Yeah. I mean, that song, I love that song cuz it's like, what do I have to do to like meet this guy?
うん。あの曲、好きなんだ。この男に会うには何をしなきゃいけないんだ、みたいな曲だから。
You know what I mean? Like, I got a fake tan. I got a personal trainer.
わかる？ フェイクタンしたし、パーソナルトレーナーもつけた。
I like, you know, I'm like really really like throwing all of this stuff at the wall.
全部、本当にこれを壁に投げつけてるみたいな。
I'm sure there are lots of tools that you're using to try to figure out how to better understand yourself and then be more present for whoever it is when they come into your
自分をもっと理解しようとして、その人が君のところに入ってきたときにもっとそこにいるためのツールを、たくさん使ってるんだろうね
life, right? Try to be the best version of yourself you can be and then leave room to grow.
人生に、だよね？ できるいちばん良い自分になろうとして、それから伸びる余地を残す。
So, through those tools, whether it's therapy or whether it's exercise or other endorphin or even partying or whatever you're going through to figure it out
そういうツールを通して、セラピーでも、運動でも、ほかのエンドルフィンでも、パーティーでも、見極めるために通ってる何でも、
um what are you understanding about about your identity or about who you are today that may or may not subconsciously be kind of creating caution or perhaps putting up some kind of barrier
自分のアイデンティティについて、今日の自分について、何がわかってきてる？ それが無意識に警戒を作ったり、何かの壁を立てたりしてるかもしれない、
between you and whoever's out there? or do you think it's just you haven't met them yet?
君と、外にいる誰かとの間に。それとも、ただまだ会ってないだけだと思う？
No, I think it's me. Yeah, I think it's me. Um cuz I meet a lot of people, you know, it's crazy.
いや、僕だと思う。うん、僕だと思う。だってたくさん人に会うし、狂ってるよ。
So, for this album, I made a list of photographers that I want to work with for the editorials cuz I kind of wanted to take a little bit more charge of how things
このアルバムのために、エディトリアルで一緒にやりたい写真家のリストを作った。ものの見え方を、もうちょっと
looked even in like magazines and stuff. And my ex-boyfriend used to photograph me all the time when we were together.
自分で握りたかったから。雑誌とかでも。元彼氏が、一緒にいたときずっと僕を撮ってたんだ。
And he's an amazing photographer and he was like kind of the like the great like love of my life I would say so far. Um and he him and I we still share dogs.
彼はすごい写真家で、今までの人生でいちばん大きな愛だったと思う。犬もまだ一緒に共有してる。
We're like you know kind of in contact but um but we're not like you know hanging out all the time and stuff. It's always nice when I see him but it's it's whatever.
連絡は取ってる感じだけど、いつも一緒にぶらぶらしてるわけじゃない。会うといつもいいけど、まあそういうことだ。
Um, and I put his name on the list of photographers almost as a joke to myself.
で、写真家のリストに彼の名前を、ほとんど自分へのジョークとして入れた。
I was like, that would be kind of crazy if like, you know, cuz we put out this little zen for my second album, Bloom, of like photos that he had taken of me.
「それ、ちょっと狂ってるよな」って。2ndアルバム『Bloom』で、彼が僕を撮った写真の小さなzenを出したから。
Yeah. I put his name on the list and I was like, it would be interesting to have these photos like 8 years later. You know, so much life has happened since then and whatever.
うん。リストに名前を入れて、「8年後にこういう写真があったら面白いよな」って。あれから人生がたくさん起きたし。
Anyways, before I knew it, it was like actually happening and they like this magazine had reached out to him to ask him if he would shoot me and I hadn't even asked him
とにかく、気づいたら実際に起きてて、この雑誌が彼に連絡して、僕を撮らないか聞いてて、僕はまだ彼に
or anything like that. So then I like panic and I'm like, "Hey, by the way, this actually like did come from me. Would you be interested?
何も頼んでなかった。だからパニックになって、「ねえ、ちなみに、これ実際僕から来たんだ。興味ある？
It's totally fine. If not, whatever." And he said yes. So he would like love to.
全然いいよ。ダメなら、まあいいし」って。彼はイエスって。やりたいって。
Wow. It was Well, the thing was I went in feeling so chill. I don't know what came over me that I was like this is not a big deal.
すごい。それは、まあ、僕は超チルな気持ちで入ったんだ。何が起きたかわからないけど、大したことじゃない、って。
Like this is going to be so fine.
これ、全然大丈夫になる、って。
Cut to we're [laughter] like doing this one shot and it's like there's the second shot of the day and there's no one else around and it's just the two of us and like
カットして、このワンショットをやってるところ。その日の2ショット目で、ほかに誰もいなくて、二人だけで、
Lost Boys by Phoebe Bridges is playing on the on speaker and he like does this and I can see like wrinkles here that he didn't have like the last time I saw him,
フィービー・ブリッジズのLost Boysがスピーカーでかかってて、彼がこうして、ここにしわが見える。前に会ったときにはなかったしわ。
you know, and it like just rocked me. Like I I was I had my rocked for a second and I like was like, "Fuck
それで僕、やられた。一瞬、僕はロックされて、「くそ、
I need to say something cuz I'm going to look really weird in this photograph if like if I don't, you know, so
何か言わなきゃ。言わないと、この写真で本当に変に見える」って。
I I I said something and had like a really really good like cry for a second and I think it was one of those moments where you know
何か言って、一瞬、本当にいい泣きをした。ああいう瞬間のひとつだったと思う、
you speak about like blocks and stuff. I'm like I think the thing of like becoming single at the same time as like work was blowing up for me in a way that I couldn't have anticipated.
ブロックとかの話をするような。シングルになったのと同時に、仕事が予想できなかった形で僕にとって爆発してたことだと思う。
And also like the fact that a lot of the people that listen to my music are also like in the dating pool that I'm trying to to date.
それに、僕の音楽を聴いてる人の多くが、僕がデートしようとしてるデーティングプールにもいるって事実。
I think it freaked me out and I went really I kind of locked down. You know what I mean?
それでビビったと思うし、本当に、なんかロックダウンした。わかる？
Yeah. And so I think I still probably have like quite a lot of work to do on on that. And it's like kind of you know what the album is.
うん。だからまだ、それについてはかなりやるべきことがあると思う。それがアルバムなんだよな。
I think what you can hopefully feel in the album, even though again it's not like that fun to acknowledge is like a person in like wanting, you know
アルバムで感じてもらえるといいのは、また認めるの楽しくないんだけど、欲してる人、
in longing and like um all the kind of like like a song like FF where it's like like drags you through. It's like that's kind of how it how it feels, you know?
憧れてる人で、FFみたいな曲は、引きずっていく感じ。そういう感じなんだよ、わかる？
Yeah. Yeah, but that's why I said it's really dressed up to go out on the town because the arrangement and the musicality around FF and Le Boy and are really like they're reaching for
うん。うん、だから街に出かけるためにちゃんと着飾ってるって言ったんだ。FFとLe Boyの周りのアレンジと音楽性が、本当に掴みにいってて
something quite euphoric even in the even in in a mid-tempo point of view. It's like they want to go out and feel something pretty euphoric through the kind of honesty and the sort of self-awareness of it.
かなり陶酔的なものを。ミドルテンポの視点から見ても。正直さと自意識を通して、かなり陶酔的な何かを感じに外へ出たいみたいな。
I think it's crazy. Your inner voice is doing a lot of work. I mean for you even to say it was a joke.
狂ってると思う。内なる声がかなり働いてる。ジョークだったって言えること自体が。
I mean, to reach out to your ex from a creative point of view and bring him so closely into you, it's an intimate experience having your photo taken
クリエイティブな視点から元彼に手を伸ばして、こんなに近くに入れるなんて、写真を撮られるのは親密な体験だよ、
especially if no one else is around. I got to ask you, when you saw the photos back, do you see yourself different the way he shoots you?
特にほかに誰もいないなら。聞きたいんだけど、写真が戻ってきたとき、彼の撮り方で自分を違って見る？
I think I do. Yeah. You know, I think like Yeah. I just think that, you know, it's you know how it is with your first love.
見ると思う。うん。うん、ただ、初恋ってそういうもんだよね。
I think it's like it's never going to it's always going to be there, you know.
絶対に、ずっとそこにあるんだと思う。
It's like um and so I was so grateful for for the experience, but I think it what it it showed me is I was like, "Oh, shit."
だからあの体験には本当に感謝してた。でもそれが見せてくれたのは、「ああ、やば」って。
like I have like I've got you know like old hangups still at this point you know and it's like um and then it's like all of a sudden in the track list like
この時点でも、古い引っかかりがまだある、って。で、急にトラックリストでは、
I didn't want to do like dancy pop songs sad longing depressed songs like because that's again that was not what was happening.
ダンシーなポップソングも、悲しい憧れの落ち込む曲も、やりたくなかった。また、起きてたことじゃなかったから。
So you go all of a sudden it's like Troy meets world and you know it's like again there's this like self-awareness there where I'm like oh yeah this is mental like I'm going
だから急にTroy meets worldみたいになって、またそこに自意識があって、「ああ、これ頭おかしいな、僕は
all around the world I'm meeting all these people I'm like dancing whatever but like and then it ends in this like kind of woodwind section that I'm like I think the kind of
世界中を回って、いろんな人に会って、踊ったりしてる、でも」って。で、木管のセクションみたいなので終わるんだけど、
like um surreal aspects of the album or the like again sort of manic thing like I I really really was interested in kind of leaning into um the layers of of all of
アルバムのシュールな側面とか、またあのマニアックな感じの層に、僕は本当に寄りかかっていきたかった。その全部の
that stuff. Did turning 30 feel profound to you?
そういうものに。30になるのは、深く感じた？
Actually, yeah. 30 was scary. 31 I feel nothing. Like I'm But 30 it was 30 was weird. Um yeah. I don't know.
実際、うん。30は怖かった。31は何も感じない。でも30は、30は変だった。うん。わからない。
I mean I I've always had like a bit of a tension with it all because like I I love my family so much and they're all in Australia and I think you know
ずっと、全部にちょっとした緊張があった。家族が大好きで、みんなオーストラリアにいて、
I've been living overseas by myself for a long time and thankfully my my family is like starting to kind of move over here.
長いこと一人で海外に住んでて、ありがたいことに家族がこっちに移り始めてる。
Like my brother Tide is living here now, my sister's living here and that's helping a lot.
ブラザー・タイドが今ここに住んでるし、妹もここに住んでて、それがかなり助けになってる。
But like, you know, I do I have I have like [snorts] um things that I care about more than my career, you know.
でも、キャリアより大事にしてることがあるんだ。
It's a crazy one. You know, that's that that is probably the ultimate sacrifice of doing anything that takes you away from home, the great adventure. You don't think about it in those first years, it's just all experience.
狂った話だよね。家から離れることをするものの、究極の犠牲はたぶんそれだ。大きな冒険。最初の何年かは考えない。全部経験なんだ。
It's all ambition and and whatever. But then eventually to your point whether it's 30 or some point you you stop and you realize like like I'm not going to have a like an infinite supply of opportunity to spend
全部野心とか、そういうもの。でも結局、君の言うところまで来ると、30でもどこかの時点でも、立ち止まって気づく。過ごす機会が無限にあるわけじゃない、って。
time with these people like life is happening and I've got to make the most of that as well and finding that balance. I think it's cool your brother worked on this record with you.
この人たちと。人生は起きてるし、それも最大限にしなきゃいけない。そのバランスを見つけること。弟がこのレコードで君とやってたの、いいよね。
That must have made a really big difference having someone who just speaks your language really inherently and totally feeling of trust when you're going through this kind of emotional change like oh who
本当に大きな違いだったはずだ。君の言葉を生まれつき話す人がいて、この感情の変化を通るときの完全な信頼。「僕は誰
am I? I'm seen as this, but I'm this. Let me put some real foundation into this.
なんだ？ こう見られてるけど、こっちが自分だ。ここに本物の土台を入れよう」
Yeah. Yeah. I mean, also, we just like I I was really interested in the album coming from like a different place other than like the recording studio, you know?
うん。うん。それに、アルバムがレコーディングスタジオ以外の、違う場所から来ることに、すごく興味があったんだ。
I just I I think like on my last one, I was so obsessed with trying to make this like perfect pop that I still love and I would like, you know
前作では、完璧なポップを作ろうとしてobsessしてて、今でも好きだし、
I'm going to continue to try and make that for my whole life probably.
たぶん一生、それを作り続けようとすると思う。
But the thing that felt more much much much more challenging to me this time was making something that felt, you know, almost like random and and like off the cuff kind of thing.
でも今回、ずっとずっと挑戦的に感じたのは、ほとんどランダムで、思いつきみたいなものを作ることだった。
And so, yeah, making it at home with my little brother and like recording my own vocals and not even knowing how to like bounce stems
だから、うん、家で弟と作って、自分のボーカルを自分で録って、ステムのバウンスの仕方すらわからなくて、
having to figure that out for the first time when I'm like sending things to mix, you know, it's like it was a really um really like thrilling musical experience.
ミックスに送るときに初めてそれを解明しなきゃいけなくて、本当にスリリングな音楽体験だった。
And also working with Jack, like Jack's process is so different from anyone else's that I've ever worked with. How how did you absorb that?
それにジャックと働くのも。ジャックのプロセスは、今まで一緒にやった誰とも全然違う。どう吸収したの？
So he I'm used to being super measured in the studio. We find a part, we find the right sound for it, we put it in, we move on to the next part.
だから彼、僕はスタジオで超慎重にやるのに慣れてる。パートを見つけて、合う音を見つけて、入れて、次のパートに進む。
You know what I mean? And like um it's pretty rare that you know sometimes I guess like the writing can happen quite quickly, but production stuff it's like very very methodical.
わかる？ 書くことはかなり速く起きることもあるけど、プロダクションはとてもとても手順どおりなんだ。
Jack is like the complete opposite. He has everything set up and ready to go. Everything is like on. And Laura, his incredible engineer that he works with all the time, is like they speak this other language.
ジャックは完全に逆。全部セットアップして、すぐ行ける。全部オンなんだ。ローラ、いつも一緒にやってるすごいエンジニア、二人は別の言語を話してるみたい。
They've been working together for like so long at this point.
この時点で、すごく長いこと一緒にやってる。
And and so it becomes this like very very very fluid like energetic experience where and he's so amazing at every instrument like and it's like instruments that I've never seen before and he's
だから、とてもとても流動的でエネルギッシュな体験になる。彼はあらゆる楽器がすごくうまくて、僕が見たことない楽器とかもあって、
got tape machines and he's running this through that and whatever and it's like he just kind of throws everything at it which honestly stresses me out like as in I I in the
テープマシンも持ってて、これをあれに通したりして、全部それに投げつける。正直それは僕をストレスにする。最初は
beginning I'm like oh my god like what is this kind of thing and then I'll sit with Laura or I'll sit with Jack and we like edit.
「なんてことだ、これ何なんだ」みたいで、それからローラと座るか、ジャックと座って、編集する。
So, how do you, if you've got Troy meets World Up and ready to go, and
じゃあ、Troy meets Worldが上がってすぐ行ける状態で、
there's like 30 40% more in it than we actually hear on the record, how do you prevent yourself from doing the thing that you trained yourself to do, which
レコードで実際聞こえるより30、40%多く入ってるとして、自分に訓練したことをやるのを、どう防ぐの？ それは
is take away some of the random elements that Jack and Laura think are going to make it magical, but you might cut them off cuz you're just like, "No, no, no.
ジャックとローラが魔法になると思ってるランダムな要素を、取り去ること。君は「いやいやいや」って切っちゃうかもしれない。
It's not who I am." They're like, "But you could be."
「それは僕じゃない」って。彼らは「でも、なれるよ」って。
Yeah. If you let go. No, totally. I think I think like I know that Jack wanted to push me, you know, and I appreciate it so much, you know, and
うん。手放せば。いや、まったく。ジャックは僕を押したかったんだと思うし、本当にありがたい。
it's like I think when I look at my like end of year, what I'm listening to
年末に、自分が聴いてるものを見ると、
I am listening to stuff that is like it's like Arthur Russell or something like that where I'm like, "Oh, this was like made from the heart."
アーサー・ラッセルみたいなものを聴いてるんだ。「ああ、これは心から作られた」って。
And like, you know, I think a lot about like furniture and the patino and like something that's actually vintage. It's like this is so cool.
家具とかパティノとか、実際にヴィンテージなものについてよく考える。これ、すごくかっこいい、って。
And it's like and I want I want that to be I wanted that to be in the music, you know?
それが音楽の中にあってほしかったんだ。
I wanted it to have like life. Like this is a this is a real lived experience more than like a pop project even necessarily. Well, it's an exercise in taste.
命があってほしかった。これは本物の生きた体験で、必ずしもポップのプロジェクト以上のもの。まあ、センスの演習だよ。
And one of the things I think that people now really really respond to you is is your overall taste.
今、人が君に本当に反応してるもののひとつは、君の全体的なセンスだと思う。
But the trick is like what do I like? As Brainos says, what do I like? Like when did you first ask yourself that question going way back?
でもトリックは、「僕は何が好きなんだ？」なんだ。ブレイノスが言うように、「僕は何が好き？」その質問を自分に初めてしたのはいつ？ ずっと昔に遡って。
When can you honestly say that you actually thought, I like that and I want to tell people about or I want I want to experience that and help others experience that.
正直に、「これ好きだ、人に伝えたい」あるいは「これを体験したい、ほかの人にも体験するのを助けたい」って実際に思ったのは、いつだと言える？
I mean, I have super early memories of music of hearing didn't know what they were at the time, but chord progressions that I really liked and I um you know like a song like Together Again by Janet Jackson.
音楽の、超初期の記憶がある。当時は何かわからなかったけど、本当に好きだったコード進行を聴いた記憶。ジャネット・ジャクソンの『Together Again』みたいな曲。
That was like a warmth that I was like, "Wo, what is this? You this is something like there's something that's evoking something in me that I I just didn't understand."
あれは温かさで、「うわっ、これ何？ 何かが僕の中の何かを呼び起こしてて、ただ理解できなかった」って。
And I knew that I wanted to hear it again. But then I think really it started to happen when I was like probably 13, 14 and started to, you know, there's like key people that come to mind.
もう一回聴きたいってわかってた。でも本当に始まりだしたのは、たぶん13、14のときで、頭に浮かぶ大事な人たちがいる。
Like I I went and saw the Lily Allen show the other night and I remember her being like the first person that I was like, "Oh, wait.
このあいだリリー・アレンのショーを見に行って、彼女が最初の人だったのを覚えてる。「ああ、待って。
songs can be like funny and smart, you know, like that made me want to write lyrics.
曲って面白くて頭いいものにもなれるんだ」って。それで歌詞を書きたくなった。
Or then like, you know, Amy Wine House was exactly the same thing where I'm like I feel so like deeply connected to her like not in any way that any I expect anyone
あるいはエイミー・ワインハウスもまったく同じで、彼女にとても深くつながってる感じがした。誰か
else to like see or understand or whatever. It's just like I just love her so much.
ほかの人に見てほしいとか理解してほしいとか、そういうんじゃなくて。ただ彼女が大好きなんだ。
Just like such a special special special artist and she was the one who really like yeah she made me want to write songs.
本当に特別な特別な特別なアーティストで、曲を書きたくさせてくれたのは彼女だった。
Um and then of course like Madonna, you know, it's like I think just I can think of these people throughout my life. Um imagine heap used to YouTube vlog and then like visually Yeah.
もちろんマドンナも。人生を通してこういう人たちを思いつく。イマジン・ヒープはYouTubeでブイログしてたし、それから視覚的に。うん。
I think it was maybe a little later in life like when I kind of got to um when I started traveling cuz I was in Perth like I didn't really get exposed to
もう少しあとだったと思う。旅を始めたとき。パースにいたから、あんまり触れてなくて
fashion and like crazy interiors and stuff like that.
ファッションとか、狂ったインテリアとか、そういうものに。
like that all came kind of like much later and um I'm I'm kind of grateful that it did because I also think it I don't know there's a lot of that like I
そういうのはずっとあとから来た感じで、あとからでよかったと思ってる。参加したくないものもたくさんあるから、
don't want to partake in as well, you know? So, it's like I think that art is like in all forms it's like you'll know if you like something and it's okay to like it.
わかる？ アートはあらゆる形で、好きならわかるし、好きでいいんだ。
It's awesome when you get to a point in your in your life where you're like it's okay if I like it and also it's okay that that amount of people agree with me
人生のある時点に着けるのは最高だよ。「好きでいいし、この人数が僕に同意するのもいい」って。
and that amount of people don't. But when you're younger and okay, let's let's paint the picture like you're in Perth. You can't inherently know who you are.
「この人数が同意しなくてもいい」。でも若いとき、よし、絵を描こう、君はパースにいる。自分が誰か、生まれつきにはわからない。
You know how you how you how you're created, how you're made, what inspires you, what titillates you, what moves you, who you love, who you're seeking.
どう作られたか、どうできてるか、何にインスパイアされるか、何にときめくか、何に動かされるか、誰を愛してるか、誰を探してるか。
But to your point, you're not really being exposed to a lot of that kind of culture and community and whatnot.
でも君の言う通り、そういう文化やコミュニティには、あんまり触れてないんだよね。
You touched on this a little bit at the beginning of the conversation when you walked into the gay bar for the first time, but
会話の最初に、初めてゲイバーに入ったときのこと、少し触れてたけど、
when you look back on that, were you were you did you have to pretend, do you think, when you were a kid?
振り返ると、子供のとき、演じなきゃいけなかったと思う？
Did you have just to try to figure it out? Oh my god. Yeah, 100%.
ただ見極めようとしてただけ？ なんてこと。うん、100%。
Yeah. Like I feel like the first, you know, 15 years of my life are just like a complete like performance. Yeah.
うん。人生の最初の15年は、完全なパフォーマンスみたいな感じなんだ。うん。
It's like a some of my earliest earliest earliest memories in my life were like of suppression of self, you know?
人生でいちばんいちばんいちばん早い記憶のいくつかは、自分の抑圧だった。
So, it's like I think maybe that's why I pursue self-expression with so much like vigor now is because I'm really grateful that I can kind of thing.
だから今、自己表現をこんなに勢いで追い求めてるのは、できることに本当に感謝してるからだと思う。
Um I remember having a I've got a friend who um the way that he would stand
友達がいて、彼の立ち方、
he would like kind of pop his hip or like hang his wrist and I would be like, "Oh my god, like pick your wrist up."
腰をちょっとポップさせたり、手首をぶら下げたりして、僕は「なんてことだ、手首を上げて」って。
cuz like I don't know if I was like we're going to get bashed or if I'm like I don't know what the the fear was but it it's a fear that was in
殴られるんじゃないか、みたいだったのか、恐怖が何だったのかわからないけど、その恐怖は
me from like the day I was born basically.
生まれた日から僕の中にあった、基本的に。
How exhausting. M that must have just been the whole time. Yeah.
どれだけ疲れるか。うーん、ずっとそうだったはずだ。うん。
That's not like oh for an hour a day.
「1日1時間だけ」みたいなのじゃない。
That's like as soon as I wake up, I have to figure out how I'm going to carry myself in a manner that protects me from the perception or the realization others may have
起きた瞬間から、自分の運び方を考えなきゃいけない。他人が持つ認識や気づきから自分を守るやり方で、
and whatever my brain tells me may occur from or like actually protects me like safety wise. Yeah. Yeah. Exactly.
脳が「こうなるかも」って言うことから、あるいは実際に安全の意味で自分を守る。うん。うん。まさに。
So, it's like but I mean it's like it influences everything at that at that age because you're also like I said you're a kid.
でもその年齢では全部に影響する。だって言ったように、子供だから。
your brain is not like fully developed and you're trying to understand this like really really really like big picture thing about the world and yourself and like your place in it and whatever
脳は完全に発達してないし、世界と自分と、その中の自分の場所についての、本当に大きい絵を理解しようとしてる。
and yeah that's Troy meets world real fast.
で、それがTroy meets worldを超高速でやるんだ。
Yeah. Exactly. Real fast. Yeah. But now I'm like anytime I feel any remnants of that I I like lean all the way in.
うん。まさに。超高速。うん。でも今は、その残りを少しでも感じたら、全部そっちに寄りかかる。
I'm like okay no I'm going to do the exact opposite of whatever my like um fight or flight is telling me to do.
「よし、闘争か逃走かがやれって言うことの、真逆をやる」って。
I went out in drag the other night for the first time like out into the world for the first time.
このあいだ、初めてドラッグで外に出た。初めて世界の中へ。
First time. How'd it feel? Scary. Like you know getting into an Uber is scary when you are a pretty girl with like a very deep voice.
初めて。どんな感じ？ 怖い。きれいな女の子で、声がとても低いときにUberに乗るのは怖いよ。
Did you feel an element of how you felt as a kid being in that cab dressed in drag?
そのタクシーで、ドラッグを着て、子供のときの感じの要素はあった？
The same%. Yeah. It's like a full flashback.
同じ%。うん。完全なフラッシュバックだ。
Yeah. But then I felt really good. Yeah.
うん。でもそのあと、本当にいい感じがした。うん。
It was fun. I had a good time.
楽しかった。いい時間だった。
I mean, it was just annoying to like it was so hot and sweaty and [laughter] I like had the hair in my face and I'm not used to having to dancing and like
ただ、暑くて汗だくで、髪が顔にかかってて、慣れてないんだ。踊るのに慣れてなくて、
performing in those heels and stuff and with the 6ft like wig on top of your head like Yeah, it's crazy.
あのヒールでパフォーマンスするのとか、頭の上に6フィートみたいなウィッグをつけて。うん、狂ってる。
Can we talk about She's the Best, the title track of the album.
『She's the Best』の話していい？ アルバムのタイトル曲。
What a beautiful tribute. Thank you. Really amazing. And I I wanted to sort of take the opportunity while we're here to talk about some of the strong female people in your life.
なんて美しいトリビュートだ。ありがとう。本当にすごい。ここにいるあいだに、君の人生の強い女性たちの話をする機会が欲しかった。
those those people that you're kind of paying tribute to either specifically or even just through the filter of the characters that you you're writing about.
具体的に、あるいは書いてるキャラクターのフィルターを通してでも、トリビュートを捧げてる人たち。
Um, outside of your the people who you lived in the house with, the people who love and know you the best who was one of the most important female role models in your life growing up?
家で一緒に住んでた人たち、君をいちばん愛して知ってる人たちの外で、育つなかでいちばん大事だった女性のロールモデルは誰？
The first person that came to my mind was um, it's so cliche, but she was my teacher at school and she is so fab. She is so fab.
最初に頭に浮かんだのは、すごいクリシェなんだけど、学校の先生で、彼女はすごくファブなんだ。すごくファブ。
She ended up becoming the principal of the school and did it all in like skinny jeans and like heels. Superstar.
結局学校の校長になって、スキニーデニムとヒールで全部やってた。スーパースター。
Superstar beyond belief and just I think saw something in me that I was probably not ready to see by myself, you know, and
信じられないスーパースターで、僕が一人じゃまだ見る準備ができてなかった何かを、僕の中に見てたと思う。
like I that was, you know, some of my earlier memories of of like just being in awe of like a woman.
女性にただ見とれてた、初期の記憶のいくつかがそれだった。
How did she nurture that in you without making it obvious enough for you to feel overly seen or scared at what she was what she'd recognized?
それを、見られすぎてるとか、気づかれたことに怖くなるほどあからさまにせず、どうやって君の中で育てたの？
I mean, this is such a random example, but I did the swimming carnival. Did you have swimming carnivals at school?
すごいランダムな例なんだけど、水泳のカーニバルをやったんだ。学校に水泳カーニバルあった？
Well, take the carnival out of it and tell me what it is. I don't know. It was just swimming competition.
カーニバルを抜いて、それが何か教えて。わからない。ただの水泳の競技だった。
Yeah. And [laughter] everyone had to I wish they called it a carnival out of it. Enjoyed it a lot more.
うん。みんなやらなきゃいけなくて、カーニバルを抜いて呼んでほしかった。もっと楽しめただろうに。
It was not a carnival. It's just like it's not a carnival when I did it, but it's compulsory. Everyone has to do it and whatever.
カーニバルじゃなかった。僕がやったときはカーニバルじゃない。でも強制で、みんなやらなきゃいけない。
And I have this horrifically traumatic experience of I could not make it more than four strokes without having to stop and like hold on to the thing and catch my breath.
ひどくトラウマな体験があって、4ストロークより先に行けなくて、止まって何かに捕まって息を整えなきゃいけなかった。
And the whole school is watching and I'm like absolutely mortified. It's like everyone's going to know that I'm gay cuz I suck at sport. And I'm like what the Anyways, the next year Fishy this like queen Yeah.
学校じゅうが見てて、完全に死にたい。スポーツが下手だから、みんなにゲイだってバレる、って。なにが、とにかく、翌年フィッシー、このクイーンが、うん。
is like you don't I was like I don't want to swim. She's like you don't have to swim you can. Which is like an exception to the rule like everyone has to swim.
「しなくていい」って。僕は泳ぎたくないって。彼女は「泳がなくていい、できる」って。みんな泳がなきゃいけないルールの例外みたいな。
Yeah. She's like, "You don't have to swim if you sing the national anthem."
うん。彼女は「国歌を歌うなら、泳がなくていい」って。
Wow. What a reinforcing. What an amazing thing.
すごい。なんて補強だ。なんてすごいことだ。
Mhm. And so, yeah, I I sang the national anthem and then I like went home.
うん。だから国歌を歌って、家に帰った。
Is it the first time you ever sang in front of anybody?
誰かの前で歌ったの、初めて？
No, but I did sing at school for the first time. So, I think it was like, you know, that definitely fostered in that environment like I was learning that I love to sing and whatever.
いや、でも学校で初めて歌った。あの環境で確実に育まれたと思う。歌うのが好きだって学んでたし。
I would love to know how quickly she figured out that that would be a really amazing way to reinforce what's special about you and take you out of the rat race of swimming
彼女がどれだけ速く、それが君の特別なものを補強するすごいやり方で、水泳のラットレースから
carnival. Totally. You know, I think it's a it's a it's a good example I think of like the kind of safety and protection that I felt from women that I haven't felt from men like
カーニバル。まったく。女性から感じた安心と保護の、いい例だと思う。男性からは感じたことない、
you know always. So during the songwriting process when we were writing she's the best. I was like, "Oh, this has been like a constant in my life."
いつも、ね。だから『She's the Best』を書いてた過程で、「ああ、これは僕の人生の定数だった」って。
Like from day one, those are the people that have really like had my back, you know, me existing
初日から、本当に僕の背中を持ってくれた人たち。僕が存在してること、
I'm so comfortable and kind of like my happiest honestly when I'm existing in the orbit of like a woman, you know, and
女性の軌道のなかにいるときがいちばん心地よくて、正直いちばん幸せなんだ。
you I think about like [snorts] like a duet with Ariana or something like that or I think about um doing the idol with Lily Rose Depp or Sweat Tour with Charlie like or
アリアナ・グランデとのデュエットとか、リリー＝ローズ・デップと『The Idol』をやったこととか、Charli xcxとのSweat Tourとか、
a video with Nicole. Or a video with Nicole. Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. It's like I I just am so so so comfortable in that world.
ニコール・キッドマンとのビデオ。ニコールとのビデオ。うん。うん。まさに。あの世界にいると、本当に本当に本当に心地いいんだ。
I like makes me think about getting ready for house parties and like I would I would get ready in like 5 minutes at home early and then go and just like watch the
ハウスパーティーの準備を思い出す。家で早めに5分で準備して、それからただ
girls get ready and we would just like talk and hang out and whatever and it was always so much more fun than the parties cuz then I would show up to the parties
女の子たちが準備するのを見て、話して、ぶらぶらして。パーティーよりずっと楽しかった。パーティーに着くと
and like the boys would be like homophobic and stuff like that and I was just like Um so yeah, I don't know.
男の子たちがホモフォビックだったりして、僕はただ。だから、うん、わからない。
I just like it was it was something that I really really just wanted to like honor and um I I I I knew immediately I was like I really want to lead with
本当に本当に称えたかったことで、すぐわかった。これを先頭にしたい、
this, you know? I'm like I know it's like not a 3minut pop song or 2 minute 30 pop song or whatever that like has like this crazy melodic thing that's super easy to get right away
これ、ね？ 3分のポップソングでも、2分30秒のポップソングでも、すぐ掴める狂ったメロディックなものがあるやつじゃないってわかってる。
or whatever. I was like I don't I don't care. like this is something that comes so um like from so deep within me that I'm just like this is exactly what I want to do right now.
どうでもよかった。僕のずっと奥から来るもので、今まさにこれがやりたいことなんだ、って。
I don't know why but in that song specifically cuz I I like sort of wrote a little melody for it and stuff and I was like this feels too contrived for the for
わからないけど、あの曲は特に、ちょっとメロディを書いたりして、これは作為的すぎる感じがした、
how heartfelt the message is. I was like it needs to feel like it is just happening in this effortless way.
メッセージがこんなに心からのものに対して。ただこの力の入らない形で起きてる感じが必要だ、って。
like the idea of trying to place it melodically and again like you know my pop brain kicks into gear where I'm like oh it should be like symmetrical you know if we're going
メロディに置こうとする考え、また僕のポップ脳がギアに入って、「対称であるべきだ、やるなら
to do this the phrasing should be the same and whatever I was like I don't want to deal with that on this song like it's going to make it feel like it's too
これをやるなら、フレージングは同じであるべき」とか。この曲ではそれに関わりたくなかった。作り込まれすぎる感じになる、
produced or too you know what I mean like I just I wanted it to feel as natural as it was and so um it just kind of like came out that way and
わかる？ ただ、あったままの自然さで感じてほしかった。だから、そういう形で出てきた感じで、
I was like yeah this is this is it but almost everybody who worked on the record touched that song in some capacity, didn't they?
「うん、これだ」って。でもレコードに関わったほとんど全員が、なんらかの形であの曲に触ったんだよね？
Or a lot of people did. I think a lot of people did. Yeah. Yeah.
あるいは多くの人が。多くの人が触ったと思う。うん。うん。
So, so everyone [clears throat] got with the program, which was even cooler because you'd imagine if you had that desire to at times pull yourself into more of a of a pop format,
だからみんなプログラムに乗った。もっとクールだった。時々もっとポップなフォーマットに自分を引っ張りたい欲望があるなら、
someone else would, too. So, everyone understood what you were trying to achieve here. The the chords are beautiful. The melody's beautiful.
ほかの誰かもそうするだろうから。みんなが、ここで達成しようとしてることを理解してた。コードが美しい。メロディが美しい。
You could actually, and this is not an insult, remove you off of it, and I'd be happy just grooving instrumental. It's gorgeous. Like, it's so beautiful and so many layers like, you know, there's like gorgeous strings on it.
これ侮辱じゃないんだけど、君を外しても、インストだけでグルーヴして幸せだよ。ゴージャスだ。こんなに美しくて、レイヤーがたくさんで、ゴージャスなストリングスがある。
And then we got Charlie XX doing the chanty thing at the end which was a nice little nod to her from both me and George who's on the wanting to take that moment
それからCharli xcxが最後にチャンティなことをやってて、僕と、入ってるジョージ両方からの、彼女への小さな頷きで、その瞬間を
to like celebrate her you know um was really fun. I think to know her is to be inspired by her.
祝いたくて。本当に楽しかった。彼女を知ることは、彼女にインスパイアされることだと思う。
Like there's there's no way that you can be around someone with that much like creative force and not just be like in awe. You just said it perfectly.
あれだけの創造の力を持つ人の周りにいて、見とれないわけがない。今、完璧に言ったね。
To know her is to be inspired by her. All that happened in the last two or three years more people got to know her. Totally.
彼女を知ることは、彼女にインスパイアされること。この2、3年で起きた全部で、もっと多くの人が彼女を知るようになった。まったく。
You know, she's been that from day one. Yep. Yeah. Which makes me so much more like fearless than I actually am.
彼女は初日からそうだった。うん。うん。それで僕は、実際の自分よりずっと恐れがなくなる。
How did you guys hold together on that tour and not just spiral off to Party Mars and never come back?
あのツアー、君らどうやって一緒に持ちこたえて、パーティー・マーズに螺旋して二度と戻ってこない、ってならなかったの？
I mean, just with each other, I think, you know. I think like one of the other reasons why that worked so you did spiral off to Party Mars at times, right?
ただお互いだけで、だと思う。うまくいったほかの理由のひとつは、時々パーティー・マーズに螺旋してたよね？
Oh, for sure. 100%. Yeah. Yeah. No, but I think like, you know, she and I were both sort of like nervous about touring cuz it's so intense and whatever.
ああ、確実に。100%。うん。うん。いや、でも彼女も僕も、ツアーについてちょっと緊張してた。すごく激しいし。
And we've known each other for so long and we have the same manager and um Brandon, our manager, was like, "Well, what if you guys like did a thing together?"
すごく長いこと知り合いで、マネージャーも同じで、マネージャーのブランドンが「二人で何か一緒にやったら？」って。
And I just didn't really know that that was an option. I was like, "Wait, what? Yeah, sure." Like that sounds incredible.
それが選択肢だって本当に知らなかった。「待って、なに？ うん、いいよ」って。信じられないくらい良さそう、って。
And then I remember, you know, I'm like very much I think the way that I grew up, I'm like be the goodest little gay boy in the world that you could possibly be.
育ち方のせいだと思うんだけど、世界でいちばん良い小さなゲイボーイでいなきゃ、って。
Like I'm I'm quite um I think like polite and whatever, you know, all that stuff. And um I remember I think it was maybe the second show and we went up on the riser thing.
かなり礼儀正しいほうだと思うし、そういう全部。覚えてるんだけど、たぶん2本目のショーで、ライザーみたいなものに上がった。
So we're like however many feet above the crowd and Charlie looks at me and she goes, "I'm so drunk." And I was like, "Wait, what?
crowdの上、何フィートも上にいて、Charli xcxが僕を見て「めっちゃ酔ってる」って。僕は「待って、なに？
How are you doing this?" Sick. This is amazing. And it just like I again like I think to just be around her is to feel this like I don't know.
どうやってこれやってるの？」 やば。これはすごい。また、ただ彼女の周りにいるだけで、この、わからない、を感じるんだと思う。
There was like this levity to to all of it that it kind of changed the trajectory of the rest of the tour for me because even though I wasn't drunk sometimes that was
全部にこの軽やかさがあって、僕にとって残りのツアーの軌道を変えた。酔ってないときもあって、それは
like a little bit maybe, but it wasn't really even about that. It was just about this like this freedom and this approach to to like life and work and whatever.
ちょっとだったかもしれないけど、本当はそれについてすらじゃなかった。この自由と、人生と仕事へのこのアプローチについてだった。
And I feel like she made me feel like a superhero version of myself, you know, which is amazing, but
彼女は僕を、自分のスーパーヒーロー版みたいに感じさせてくれた。それはすごいことだけど、
then also probably is like now why I made this album because there was this like version of myself that I think um I started to be like, well, wait a second.
たぶん今、このアルバムを作った理由でもある。自分のこのバージョンがあって、「まあ、ちょっと待って」ってなり始めた。
Cuz I don't feel like that all the time.
だって、ずっとそう感じてるわけじゃないから。
You can't take it home. Yeah. I couldn't take it home. I wish that I could or not. Because when you take a home, that's when you spend 30 years doing drugs on your own, right?
家には持って帰れない。うん。家には持って帰れなかった。持って帰れたらいいのに、あるいはよくない。家を持って帰ると、一人で30年ドラッグをやるときだから、だよね？
Yeah. [snorts] You know, I mean, I've interviewed quite a few people who eventually drop it after a much longer amount of time.
うん。かなり長い時間のあとで、結局それを落とす人を、かなりインタビューしてきた。
And um they'll tell you that like a lot of that behavior occurs because they don't like facing the person they are when they're not the superhero version of themselves.
その行動の多くは、スーパーヒーロー版じゃないときの自分と向き合うのが好きじゃないから起きる、って言うんだ。
Mhm. So that's where the distraction by self-destruction kicks in, right? Okay. So maybe it's not all bad. Maybe not all bad. Plus, it's not like you're not partying on this record, right?
うん。そこで自己破壊による気晴らしが入ってくるんだよね？ よし。じゃあ全部悪いわけじゃないかも。全部悪くはないかも。それに、このレコードでパーティーしてないわけじゃないよね？
Party in the bush. Party in the tree. Totally.
パーティー・イン・ザ・ブッシュ。木のパーティー。まったく。
And again, like it's so important to me to like pay tribute to that side of my life. Joy is an act of resistance.
また、人生のその側にトリビュートを捧げるのは、僕にとってすごく大事なんだ。喜びは抵抗の行為だ。
I'm so happy that we're coming out of the AMC era of Nicole Kidman, which was iconic in itself, and we're now in the mother era of Nicole Kidman, if I may say.
ニコール・キッドマンのAMC時代から出られてすごく嬉しい。それ自体アイコニックだったし、今はニコール・キッドマンのマザー時代だ、言っちゃえば。
Yeah. Yeah. I mean, Adella. Yep. you. Yeah.
うん。うん。アデラ。うん。君。うん。
It's like pop music is like it's always been you.
ポップミュージックって、ずっと君だったみたいな。
Yeah, totally. I mean, she she's everything. Yeah. Like truly.
うん、まったく。彼女は全部だよ。本当に。
Come on, let's pay tribute. Go. Let's go. From your through your filter, through the choice of our own filter. You got her in a video, dude. So, you were in a movie with her.
さあ、トリビュートしよう。行け。行こう。君のフィルターから、俺ら自身のフィルターの選び方を通して。ビデオに彼女入れたじゃん。彼女と映画に出たんだ。
You know her, but also you understand why everyone's obsessed with her. So, what is it? It's like I mean, it's an energetic thing. I think you know when like somebody walks into a room.
彼女を知ってるし、みんながなぜ彼女に夢中かもわかってる。じゃあ何なんだ？ エネルギー的なものだと思う。誰かが部屋に入ってくるとき、わかるんだよね。
Weirdly this is also Dual Lia. She also has this but they walk in and I don't know if it's like a physical like statuesque thing or if it's like star power or if it's like their openness in the
変なことに、これデュアル・リアもそうなんだ。彼女もこれを持ってて、入ってきて、身体的な彫像みたいなものなのか、スターの力なのか、顔の開きなのか、
face and the I don't know what it is but it's like and obviously they're the most like famous people in the world but I toured with DA in 2016.
何なのかわからないけど、そういう感じで、もちろん世界でいちばん有名な人たちなんだけど、2016年にDAとツアーした。
She opened for me, which is hilarious. And she it was the same. Like I knew I was just like, "Oh, fuck." Yeah.
彼女が僕の前座だった、それがおかしい。同じだった。「ああ、くそ」ってなった。うん。
There's something about this girl like and so um Nicole's I think always I'm sure always had that. And um it's just about kind of like praising it.
この子には何かある、って。ニコールは、きっといつもそれを持ってたと思う。それを称えることなんだ。
She deserves it. You know what I mean? Like what a what a queen. And I also obviously she's Australian. So it's like and Mulan Rouge was like one of my awakenings in life.
彼女はそれに値する。わかる？ なんてクイーンだ。それに彼女はオーストラリア人だ。『ムーラン・ルージュ』は人生の目覚めのひとつだった。
Like you talk about taste and and I remember that being like the weirdest movie that I had ever seen at the time. I was probably like eight.
センスの話をしてたけど、あのとき見たなかでいちばん変な映画だったのを覚えてる。たぶん8歳くらい。
Yeah. Um and I I remember being just like spellbound by her in it. And so I've I've loved her ever since.
うん。彼女にただ魅了されてたのを覚えてる。あれ以来、ずっと好きなんだ。
When you started out doing this, when we when we first met, it was it was around Blue Neighborhood and um I think the EP had just come out and I don't know if
これをやり始めたとき、俺らが初めて会ったとき、『Blue Neighbourhood』のあたりで、EPが出たばかりだったと思う。
it was one of the first interviews you did, but it felt like it to me. You felt like you were holding on. I don't want to give away.
君がやった最初のインタビューのひとつだったかわからないけど、俺にはそう感じた。君は掴んでるように感じた。渡したくない、って。
I'm trying to find a balance. And I would be fully embrace the pop star thing. Mhm.
バランスを探そうとしてる。ポップスターのことを完全に受け入れようとしてた。うん。
You know, you remember being in sessions for that album and being like, it's too pop. It's too pop. I don't want to. It's too pop.
あのアルバムのセッションにいて、「ポップすぎる。ポップすぎる。やりたくない。ポップすぎる」ってなってたの、覚えてるよね。
It was almost like you were afraid to let go into that space that you've suddenly become so um important in. Oh, thank you. And two, so I wanted to ask you this and now's the time.
急にこんなに大事になったその空間に、手放して入るのが怖かったみたいだった。ありがとう。で二つ、これを聞きたかったんだ。今がそのときだ。
When did that change? When did you when did you decide that you know what, I kind of know who I am in this music space and I know what path I'm on and I'm going to I'm
それはいつ変わった？ いつ、この音楽の空間で自分が誰かだいたいわかって、どの道にいるかわかって、僕は、僕は
going to embrace it wholeheartedly. I think in its fullest version probably before something to give each other in between the lockdowns the spending time at home spending time with my family whatever that stuff made me feel it
心から受け入れるって決めたの？ いちばん完全な形では、たぶん something to give each other の前、ロックダウンの合間、家で過ごして、家族と過ごして、そういうものが感じさせて、
reminded me of everything that I already kind of like have and it made me feel like bulletproof.
すでに持ってるもの全部を思い出させて、防弾みたいに感じさせた。
I was like, "Oh, none of this like matters in a way that's going to affect me in like the things that I really really need in my life, which
「こういうことは、人生で本当に本当に必要なものに影響する形では、大事じゃない」って。
is like love for my family." And it made me like fearless kind of thing. And so I think that that was really when I was like, "Okay, you know what?
家族への愛みたいな。それで恐れがなくなった感じ。本当にそのときだったと思う。「よし、わかった。
I'm going to like I'm not afraid to like kind of make some noise and like take up some space."
音を立てて、場所を取るのが怖くない」って。
cuz I always think that's sort of another like side effect probably of of growing up in the closet was just like not not wanting to take up too much space or bring too
クローゼットで育った副作用のもうひとつは、場所を取りすぎたくないとか、注目を
much attention to myself. And um and so yeah, the idea of like my best friend Leelin and I, we always say like, "Oh, come out with your dick swinging."
自分に集めすぎたくない、だったから。で、うん、親友のリーリンと僕は、いつも「おお、チン振ってカムアウトしろ」って言うんだ。
Like, you know, the idea of coming out like that kind of with with something as like bombastic as Rush was very like super thrilling to me, you know, and
『Rush』みたいにド派手なものとともに、そういうカムアウトをするアイデアは、僕にとって超スリリングだった。
it was kind of like the first time in my life where I was like, "Yeah, it." Like, I'm going to try and do coro and I'm going to like just really really go for it.
人生で初めて「うん、やる」みたいになった。コロをやろうとして、本当に本当に取りにいく、って。
Like um and that was really really fun.
それは本当に本当に楽しかった。
It's so interesting how that album though has led you to this place and I guess the the question is has it made you more open and available to this thing that you seek
あのアルバムが君をこの場所に連れてきたの、面白いよね。質問は、それが君をもっとオープンにして、求めてるこのものに対して使えるようにしたか、だと思う
do you think making this music has it made you better understand how to clear that pathway for a meaningful relationship in your life that thing that you've openly said on the record you're
この音楽を作ったことで、意味のある関係への道をクリアする仕方をもっと理解できたと思う？ レコードで公に、探してるって言ってるあのもの。
kind of searching for? I think I think in the same way that like therapy has Yeah. Yeah, I mean it's like such a cliche to talk about music like that, but
セラピーがそうであるのと同じように、だと思う。うん。うん、音楽をそういうふうに話すのはすごいクリシェだけど、
um putting pen to paper, whether it's like journaling or talking to a therapist or whatever
ペンを紙に置くこと、日記でも、セラピストと話すことでも、
like I do think kind of offloading these things um does make you feel lighter and kind of help you understand yourself a little bit.
こういうものを降ろすことは、軽くして、自分をちょっと理解する助けになると思う。
Also, there's this weird thing I think with like being sort of perceived in the in the public in any way where it's almost like now that I've acknowledged it
それに、公の場で何らかの形で見られることの、変なことがある。認めてしまった今、
I can move through the world in a more genuine way. Like I feel like everyone's up to date, you know?
もっと本物の形で世界を通っていける。みんなが最新を知ってる感じ。わかる？
Like, don't you think it's the opposite? Don't you think you're going to have people queuing around the around the block listening to La Boy wondering if they're La Boy and it's going to be, you know what I mean?
逆だと思わない？ ブロックの周りに列ができて、La Boyを聴きながら、自分がLa Boyかどうか思ってる人たちがいると思わない？ わかる？
Maybe. I don't know. Hopefully that'll be cool.
かも。わからない。それがクールだといいけど。
Um, but no, I mean like I I was one of the kind of like big moments of making the album was I was sitting in the pool with someone and it's like one
でも、いや、アルバムを作るなかの大きな瞬間のひとつは、誰かとプールに座ってて、
of my friends and I was like damn I have not hooked up with anyone in like a really long time and he was like what Troy what about Rush?
友達の一人で、「やば、かなり長いこと誰ともフックアップしてない」って。彼は「なに、トロイ、『Rush』はどうしたの？」って。
And I was like, "Oh, wo, like I think the world might see a different version."
僕は「おっ、世界は違うバージョンを見てるかもしれない」って。
And and that like sort of disconnect made me actually feel really uncomfortable where I was like, "Oh, I kind of feel like I need to before I can maybe this is not true.
そのズレが、実際すごく居心地悪くさせた。「ああ、たぶんこれが本当じゃないかもしれない前に、なんか必要かも」って。
I don't know, but I should talk about this in therapy." But before I can like move through my life in a way that feels more genuine
わからないけど、セラピーでこれについて話すべきだ、って。もっと本物に感じる形で人生を通る前に、
I need to kind of like acknowledge it or tell people about it or something like that and be like, "No, this is actually where I am right now."
それを認めるか、人に話すか、何かして、「いや、今の僕は実際ここなんだ」ってなる必要がある、って。
Yeah. And now my narrative is like hopelessly single, looking for a boyfriend, whatever. Sure. But at least like I'm up to date. Like everyone's kind of current now, you know?
うん。今の僕の物語は、絶望的にシングルで、彼氏を探してる、とか。たしかに。でも少なくとも最新だ。みんなが今を知ってる。わかる？
So what the is dating like then? If that's like if that's the bat signal.
じゃあデートってどんななんだ？ それがバットシグナルみたいなものなら。
Yeah. I don't know. We'll see. Like I Do you like it? Is dating fun? I mean, you're talking to someone who's been married for 27 years. Genuine question.
うん。わからない。見てみよう。好き？ デートは楽しい？ 27年結婚してる人に聞いてるんだよ。本気の質問。
Sometimes. Yeah, sometimes it's really fun. I like meeting new people and I like talking to people. I think that um sometimes it's really bad.
ときどき。うん、ときどき本当に楽しい。新しい人に会うのも、人と話すのも好き。ときどき本当にひどい。
What's a bad date like? Like a job interview kind of vibe, you know, where it's just like a bit boring or something and you're just kind of going back and forth on things.
悪いデートってどんな？ 就職面接みたいなバイブ。ちょっと退屈で、行ったり来たりしてるだけ、みたいな。
Um like I really value funny. Yeah. Yeah. So I really want it to be fun and funny.
面白いことを本当に大事にしてる。うん。うん。だから楽しくて面白くてほしい。
If they know who you are, do you prefer they're upfront about that?
相手が君が誰か知ってるなら、それについて率直でいてほしい？
Um yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Like I think the only time I ever get out about that is if someone has not been like truthful about it.
うん。うん。うん。うん。うん。それについてムカッと出るのは、誰かがそれについて正直じゃなかったときだけだと思う。
Like I I don't care if you don't know me and I don't care if you do. Um I think the only thing that I care about is if you're like acting weird about it, you know?
僕を知らなくても気にしないし、知ってても気にしない。気にするのは、それについて変なふうに振る舞ってるときだけ。わかる？
Like Yeah, I've had that happen. Have you gotten accustomed to it though? I mean you are a really visible human being and I mean you work on screen as well.
うん、それはあった。でも慣れてきた？ 君は本当に目立つ人間だし、画面でも仕事してるし。
um idol was problematic for a lot of people in a lot of different ways and whatever cool yada y and all the back all the stories about the production and this that and
『The Idol』はいろんな人にとって、いろんな形で問題があったし、クールとかとか、制作の裏話とかこれとか
the third but it was everyone watched it.
三つ目とか。でもみんな見てた。
Mhm. [clears throat] Everyone watched it. I mean my association with that show is I made like two lifelong friends out of that show.
うん。みんな見てた。あの番組との僕の関わりは、生涯の友達を二人作ったことだ。
Lily Rose and Rachel Sennet. Like those are my girls. and having I mean going to the same place every day.
リリー＝ローズとレイチェル・セネット。あの子たちが僕の女の子たちだ。毎日同じ場所に行くこと。
Yeah. Being with them, it was like high school. Like I literally I was like, "Oh, this is like I have my two best friends and we're in high school together."
うん。彼女たちといるのは、高校みたいだった。文字どおり「ああ、親友が二人いて、一緒に高校にいる」って。
It was that vibe. And so I have such a like positive um memory of that whole time.
あのバイブだった。だからあの時間全体に、すごくポジティブな記憶がある。
And again, another example, I think, of like feeling kind of invincible on the other side of something because I was like, "Oh, wow." Um, I had such a good time through through this whole kind of like experience.
また別の例だと思う。何かの向こう側で無敵に感じる。「おお」って。この経験全体を通して、すごくいい時間だった。
Um, that that I think also made me feel really emboldened uh to be like, okay, I'm going to like do what I want and do what feels right, you know?
それも、大胆にしたと思う。「よし、やりたいことをやる、正しいと感じることをやる」って。わかる？
Do you like the acting side of things? Yeah, I really do. I I definitely want to do more of it. Yeah. It's a very different discipline, though.
演技の側は好き？ うん、本当に好き。もっとやりたい。うん。でもすごく違う領域だよね。
And you've I mean you talk about the person who wants to kind of hold on to the architecture of your music as much as you can and be involved in every aspect of
君は、音楽の建築をできる限り握って、あらゆる側面に関わりたい人の話をしてる。
it. Sit next to you know engineers and producers and figure out how you want arrangements to go. You can't do that on set. Like you got to literally hand it to somebody.
エンジニアやプロデューサーの隣に座って、アレンジをどうしたいか解明する。セットではそれはできない。文字どおり誰かに渡さなきゃいけない。
You're watching on the couch with the rest of us. That's sort of my issue with it.
残りの俺らと一緒にソファで見てる。それが俺の問題なんだ。
I think is like I would love to maybe I need to like try producing something or something like that cuz I would love to I love every part of the process so much.
何かをプロデュースしてみる必要があるかも。プロセスの全部が大好きだから。
Um, like I grew up, you know, editing video and photo and um, I I still will sometimes like retouch things or design stuff myself, you know like I really really love being super hands-on with everything.
ビデオと写真の編集をして育ったし、今でもときどきレタッチしたり、自分でデザインしたりする。全部に超ハンズオンでいるのが本当に好きなんだ。
So, showing up and doing my part and leaving is it's not satisfying.
だから、顔を出して自分のパートをやって帰るのは、満足しない。
It's not satisfying 100%. Yeah. Yeah. You're a process guy. I can tell. It's funny. I was so um I swear I told you how amazing I'm sure everyone else did.
100%満足しない。うん。うん。君はプロセスの人だ。わかるよ。面白い。すごく、誓って、どれだけすごいか君に言ったと思う。ほかのみんなも言ったと思う。
amazing that ad was. It is something that you have an eye that you have for that kind of stuff.
あの広告がすごかった。そういうものへの目を、君は持ってるんだ。
Is that your getting back to Gandalf, is that your seat on the elephant ship when you don't want to dance anymore or you want to take a break?
Gandalfに戻ると、もう踊りたくないとき、休みたいときの、象の船の座席はそれ？
Is that in a weird way? Um, yeah, one of them. I think, you know, like I think I definitely have ambitions of having a family and and stuff like that.
変な意味で？ うん、そのうちのひとつ。家族を持ちたいって野心は確実にあると思う。
So, I think eventually I'll I'll want to do something else.
だからそのうち、何かほかのことをしたくなると思う。
But I I really feel not that pressed about it because I I do get so much joy out of like every part of the process for all of these different things that I
でもそれについてそんなに迫られてる感じは本当にしない。こういういろんなことの、プロセスの全部からすごく喜びを得てるから。
do. And I as long as I feel like I'm utilizing my, you know, like creativity, I'm I'm really happy.
自分のクリエイティビティを使えてる感じがする限り、本当に幸せなんだ。
Like I think there's infinite versions of that, you know, whether I'm like writing the music for a play one day or something, you know
それの無限のバージョンがあると思う。いつか劇の音楽を書くとか、
like something really challenging that's going to like that I really have to like sink my teeth into and it means that I just like commit to doing that for, you know
本当に挑戦的で、歯を食いしばって噛みつかなきゃいけないようなもの。それに、それをやることにコミットするってこと、
6 months or something like that. Uh like stepping like the public eye stuff is not really it's never been like the motivating factor for me.
6ヶ月とか。公の目に立つことは、僕の動機になったことは本当にない。
I I love touring because I built the show and I'm super excited to show people the show and everything. Um more so than necessarily like the performance itself.
ツアーが好きなのは、ショーを作って、人にショーを見せるのが超ワクワクするから。パフォーマンスそのものより、むしろ。
Yeah. Process. Yeah. The beautiful thing is that uh and I and I say this purely as a friend like you can do all of that and have a family.
うん。プロセス。うん。美しいのは、純粋に友達として言うんだけど、その全部をやって、家族も持てる。
That's the beautiful thing. Like they want you to be inspired and busy and doing cool cuz that's what they that's how they get exposed to it. That's how they get inspired.
それが美しいところだ。彼らは君にインスパイアされてて、忙しくて、クールなことをしててほしい。そうやってそれに触れるから。そうやってインスパイアされる。
That's how they see what's possible. Yeah. I think I just really want like at least when when I've got like babies, I want to take time off.
そうやって、何が可能か見る。うん。少なくとも赤ちゃんがいるときは、休みを取りたいんだ。
Yeah, definitely have to do that. Yeah, because you won't get those years back. But then once as soon as they can walk, put them on your hip and move.
うん、絶対そうしなきゃ。うん、その年は戻ってこないから。でも歩けるようになったらすぐ、腰に乗せて動け。
Yeah. Nice. My older brother's got two kids and they I mean they've been to New York. They It's like three and 8 months and they just they just go for it.
うん。いいね。兄に子供が二人いて、ニューヨークに来たことがある。3歳と8ヶ月で、ただ突き進むんだ。
I mean, this is a a beautiful life that you're building for yourself, Troy. This is a really beautiful life and it's it's not without its work and its challenges and and the things you've had to figure out.
これは君が自分のために築いてる美しい人生だよ、トロイ。本当に美しい人生で、仕事も挑戦も、見極めなきゃいけなかったこともある。
I mean, going right back to those early days in Perth right through to now. Um, what are you most proud of about yourself today, right now?
パースの初期の日から、今までずっと。今日、今この瞬間、自分についていちばん誇りに思ってることは何？
Um, I think I I guess like the um the spaces that and it almost felt like kind of unintentional but like the spaces that I've maybe helped create like the environment at my
たぶん、空間だと思う。ほとんど意図してない感じだったけど、僕が作るのを手伝えたかもしれない空間。たとえば
shows for example or um yeah like I think I think kind of just like creating a space where people like a younger version of me could have gone and and maybe had that
ショーの環境とか。僕の若いバージョンが行って、
moment that I had in Cape Town in like the nightclub or whatever where I'm like, "Oh, wow." Like this is what it feels like to be like safe and whatever.
ケープタウンのナイトクラブとかであったあの瞬間を持てたかもしれない空間。「おお」って。安全でいる感じはこうなんだ、みたいな。
Hopefully I've, you know, like created that for for some people. Um, that's probably like the thing. I'm pulling off a very strong developing mullet. Thank you. Thank you.
何人かのために、それを作れてたらいいな。たぶんそれがそのことだ。かなり強い、育ちかけのマレットを決めてるね。ありがとう。ありがとう。
What do you reckon of the ratty? It's getting there. I mean, the thing long enough yet. No, it it doesn't jump out at you, but it's definitely the makings of something special.
ラッティはどう思う？ そこまで来てる。まだ十分長くない。いや、飛び出してはこないけど、確実に何か特別なものの作りかけだ。
Thanks. I would say maybe the most outwardly Australian thing you've done in a long time is that haircut. Yeah. Nice.
ありがとう。長いあいだで、君がいちばん外向きにオーストラリアなのは、その髪型かもしれない。うん。いいね。
Right now. Oh yeah. Well, I mean you Melbourne like I feel like Party in the Bush like you know that song sounds like Melbourne to me, you know.
今まさに。ああ、うん。メルボルンだよ、パーティー・イン・ザ・ブッシュは、俺にはあの曲がメルボルンに聞こえるんだ。わかる？
Um, but also cuz it's the strongest your Australian accent's ever sounded on potty in the park. Potty in the park, potty in the bush.
でも、君のオーストラリア訛りが今まででいちばん強く聞こえたのが、ポッティ・イン・ザ・パークなんだよ。ポッティ・イン・ザ・パーク、ポッティ・イン・ザ・ブッシュ。
American manager says it sounds like I'm saying potty like and it's like about a dog going potty in the park, potty in the bush, potty under the bridge, potty at the restaurant.
アメリカ人のマネージャーが、僕がポッティって言ってるみたいだって。犬が公園でおしっこしてる話みたいで、ポッティ・イン・ザ・パーク、ポッティ・イン・ザ・ブッシュ、橋の下でポッティ、レストランでポッティ。
I'm a New Zealander and it is shocking to me the first time I heard it cuz it's just so unapologetic.
俺はニュージーランド人で、初めて聴いたときショックだった。全然謝ってないから。
Party in the park. It's amazing. So funny. And with the mullet.
パーティー・イン・ザ・パーク。すごい。面白い。マレットも一緒に。
Well, what am I supposed to do? It's so AFL.
じゃあ僕はどうすればいいの？ めっちゃAFLだよ。
Like put on a American accent for it. No, you have to be authentically yourself. That's how I say those words.
それにアメリカ訛りを載せろ、って。いや、本物の自分でいなきゃ。僕はそう発音するんだ。
But you have to admit that to some degree you've been somewhat of a of an international alien imp for a long time floating through one sort of pop room to another.
でもある程度、長いこと国際的なエイリアンのインプみたいに、ポップの部屋から別の部屋へ漂ってたことは認めなきゃだよね。
No one's quite, you know, you ask people where Troy Saban's from, they're like somewhere 300,000 light years away. No, no, no. He's from Perth. Yeah.
誰もよくわからなくて、トロイ・サバンはどこ出身って聞くと、30万光年くらい先のどこか、って。いやいや、パース出身だよ。うん。
I think I I've toyed with the idea of trying to get like a cool sort of like Madonna accent, right?
かっこいいマドンナ訛りみたいなものを取ろうと、いじったことはあると思う。
Oh, so somewhere in between. Something Bronson. Yes. Yes. Good. Good example. Nicole. Like Nicole, she can turn it on though. Really?
ああ、その中間のどこか。サムシング・ブロンソン。うん。うん。いい。いい例。ニコール。ニコールみたいに、彼女は切り替えられるけど。ほんと？
She's on the red carpet in Australia. Oh, okay. Nice. Yeah, she knows how to slide back in.
オーストラリアのレッドカーペットにいる。ああ、わかった。いいね。うん、彼女は滑って戻る方法を知ってる。
I just think it's kind of like fab. Like the random like it's like full Australian. It's like how are you?
なんかファブだと思うんだ。ランダムに、完全なオーストラリアで。「調子どう？」みたいな。
I'm like, wait, what? Where did that come from? But um [laughter] but I don't think I can do it.
僕は「待って、なに？ どこからそれ出てきたの？」って。でも、僕にはできないと思う。
No. Party in the park. Party in the park.
いや。パーティー・イン・ザ・パーク。パーティー・イン・ザ・パーク。